Mary Mitchell P015 P015
Stage
Mary Mitchell Collection
1960-1975
Stage
P015
1 box
Biographical / Historical
Mary E. A. Mitchell, a photographer and historian, was born in Minneapolis, Minnesota and attended Wellesley College. She moved to Washington, DC in 1953 and lived there until the death of her husband in 1985 when she moved to Newton, Connecticut to be closer to here two daughters. Ms. Mitchell has written several books on Washington, including: A Walk in Georgetown (1966, Barre Publishers), Divided Town (1968, Barre Publishers), Washington: Portrait of the Capital (1972, Barre Publishers), Glimpses of Georgetown (1983, The Road Street Press), and Chronicles of Georgetown Life, 1865-1900 (1986, Seven Locks Press).
Custodial History
There is no deed of gift and it uncertain as to how the library acquired these photographs. A hand written note appears on the original storage envelope indicating it was donated to the Library in 1975.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 86 packages of strip negatives. Some packages contained multiple negatives bringing the total number of strip negatives to 97. The strip negatives contain between one and seven images, which brings the total number of images in the collection to 372. According to the hand written note, the donation of the negatives occurred shortly after the publication of her third book, Washington: Portrait of the Capital (1972, Barre Publishers). After processing the collection it became clearly evident eighty-five or more of these did in fact appear in her book. All images were taken by Ms. Mitchell and range in date from the mid-1960s thru 1975 (year of donation). Images are of scattered locations throughout the city, however there are areas of concentration including the Capitol building, Chinatown, Dupont Circle, National Mall, and Lafayette Square.
Photographs; Urban renewal; Gentrification
- Series 1
  - Bush the old fire dog (tombstone) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bush the old fire dog (tombstone), undated (Item 1)
  - Unknown building (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Unknown building, undated (Item 1)
  - Union Hotel – Georgetown (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Union Hotel – Georgetown, undated (Item 1)
  - Surratt Boarding House – 604 H Street, NW (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Surratt Boarding House – 604 H Street, NW, undated (Item 1)
      Scope and Contents
      View from parking lot across the street
    - Surratt Boarding House – 604 H Street, NW, undated (Item 2)
    - Surratt Boarding House – 604 H Street, NW, undated (Item 3)
  - Lincoln Memorial (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln Memorial, undated (Item 1)
      Close view of Daniel Chester French's Lincoln statue
    - Lincoln Memorial, undated (Item 2)
  - Treasury Department (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Treasury Department, undated (Item 1)
      Alexander Hamilton statue – South entrance
    - Treasury Department, undated (Item 2)
  - Lafayette Square (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lafayette Square, undated (Item 1)
      Rochambeau statue
    - Lafayette Square, undated (Item 2)
      Metro bus with "exact fare" sign
  - US Capitol (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 1)
      Group of people near lamppost – East side
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 2)
      Lampposts on east side – Capitol in background
  - US Capitol – Window detail (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - US Capitol – Window detail, undated (Item 1)
  - US Capitol dome and John Marshall Statue (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - US Capitol dome and John Marshall Statue, undated (Item 1)
  - US Capitol – west steps (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - US Capitol – west steps, undated (Item 1)
      Detail of handrail with man coming down steps
    - US Capitol – west steps, undated (Item 2)
      Looking down the west steps toward the National Mall
  - View of St. John's Church – Lafayette Square (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - View of St. John's Church – Lafayette Square, undated (Item 1)
      View of Church on a rainy day
    - View of St. John's Church – Lafayette Square, undated (Item 2)
  - Organization of American States Building (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Organization of American States Building, undated (Item 1)
      Statue of Isabella Catolica
    - Organization of American States Building, undated (Item 2)
      Statue of Isabella Catolica (negative damaged)
    - Organization of American States Building, undated (Item 3)
  - Lafayette Square (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lafayette Square, undated (Item 1)
      Bird on park bench in Lafayette Square
    - Lafayette Square, undated (Item 2)
      People walking on path in Lafayette Square
  - Old Patent Office (National Portrait Gallery) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Old Patent Office (National Portrait Gallery), undated (Item 1)
      Exterior view of Old Patent Office from inside store window
    - Old Patent Office (National Portrait Gallery), undated (Item 2)
      Exterior view of Old Patent Office from intersection of 9th and F Streets
  - Henderson Castle (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Henderson Castle, undated (Item 1)
      Children playing on/near gates to Henderson Castle
    - Henderson Castle, undated (Item 2)
  - 1013-1021 7th Street, NW (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1013-1021 7th Street, NW, undated (Item 1)
      Looking south along 7th Street
    - 1013-1021 7th Street, NW, undated (Item 2)
      Looking north along 7th Street at intersection with New York Avenue
    - 1013-1021 7th Street, NW, undated (Item 3)
  - US Capitol (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 1)
      Corncob toped column at US Capitol
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 2)
  - Old Pan-American Building (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Old Pan-American Building, undated (Item 1)
      Column with face on corner
    - Old Pan-American Building, undated (Item 2)
    - Old Pan-American Building, undated (Item 3)
  - Howard University (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 1)
      Mural on Howard University Campus
    - Howard University, undated (Item 2)
      Campus view with Founders Library in background
  - Dupont Circle (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dupont Circle, undated (Item 1)
      View of the circle taken from atop a building
    - Dupont Circle, undated (Item 2)
    - Dupont Circle, undated (Item 3)
  - Kennedy Center (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 1)
      View of the Grand Foyer
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 2)
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 3)
      Kennedy bust in Grand Foyer
  - Library of Congress (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Library of Congress, undated (Item 1)
      Main reading room in Jefferson Building taken from observation room
    - Library of Congress, undated (Item 2)
    - Library of Congress, undated (Item 3)
  - National Mall (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - National Mall, undated (Item 1)
      Independence Avenue – Construction of Hirshhorn Museum
    - National Mall, undated (Item 2)
      Constitution Avenue – National Archives
    - National Mall, undated (Item 3)
  - St. Elizabeth's Hospital (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 1)
      View from St. Elizabeth's looking west
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 2)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 3)
  - Indonesian Embassy – 2020 Massachusetts Avenue (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Indonesian Embassy – 2020 Massachusetts Avenue, undated (Item 1)
      View of embassy from park across the street
    - Indonesian Embassy – 2020 Massachusetts Avenue, undated (Item 2)
    - Indonesian Embassy – 2020 Massachusetts Avenue, undated (Item 3)
  - White House (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - White House, undated (Item 1)
      Chandelier in North portico at White House
    - White House, undated (Item 2)
      People standing outside north entrance to the White House
    - White House, undated (Item 3)
    - White House, undated (Item 4)
      North entrance of the White House with portico pillars in foreground
    - White House, undated (Item 5)
  - US Capitol (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 1)
      Wheat topped columns inside US Capitol
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 2)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 3)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 4)
  - St. John's Church (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 1)
      Cupola of St. John's Church in Lafayette Square
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 2)
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 3)
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 4)
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 5)
    - St. John's Church, undated (Item 6)
  - US Supreme Court (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 1)
      North side of Supreme Court with flag and Capitol Dome
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 2)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 3)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 4)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 5)
      West pediment of Supreme Court building
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 6)
  - Congressional Cemetery (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 1)
      Latrobe designed monuments for members of congress who died in office
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 2)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 3)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 4)
      Detail of Congressional monument dedicated to William Thornton
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 5)
      General view of cemetery with chapel in background
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 6)
  - St. Elizabeth's Hospital (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 1)
      Looking west at Washington from St. Elizabeth's
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 2)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 3)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 4)
    - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, undated (Item 5)
    - US Navy Yard Quarters, undated (Item 6)
  - Christ Church – Capitol Hill (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Christ Church – Capitol Hill, undated (Item 1)
      Christ Church on Capital Hill
    - Christ Church – Capitol Hill, undated (Item 2)
    - Christ Church – Capitol Hill, undated (Item 3)
      Fenced in pond – National Zoo?
    - Christ Church – Capitol Hill, undated (Item 4)
  - Congressional Cemetery (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 1)
      Detail of Congressional monument dedicated to Henry Clay
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 2)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 3)
    - Congressional Cemetery, undated (Item 4)
  - Women's Democratic Club (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Women's Democratic Club, undated (Item 1)
      British Embassy
    - Women's Democratic Club, undated (Item 2)
      Women's Democratic Club
    - Women's Democratic Club, undated (Item 3)
    - Women's Democratic Club, undated (Item 4)
      Volta Laboratory and Bureau Building
  - US Marine Corps band (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 1)
      US Marine Corps band
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 2)
      US Marine Corps color guard
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 3)
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 4)
      US Marine Corps band – Parade
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 5)
    - US Marine Corps band, undated (Item 6)
  - US Marine Corps Band (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - US Marine Corps Band, undated (Item 1)
    - US Marine Corps Band, undated (Item 2)
    - US Marine Corps Band, undated (Item 3)
    - US Marine Corps Band, undated (Item 4)
    - US Marine Corps Band, undated (Item 5)
  - Streets Scenes (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Streets Scenes, undated (Item 1)
      Unknown street scene
    - Streets Scenes, undated (Item 2)
    - Streets Scenes, undated (Item 3)
    - Streets Scenes, undated (Item 4)
    - Streets Scenes, undated (Item 5)
  - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 1)
      Street scene - New Hampshire Avenue
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 2)
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 3)
      House doorway (Middle East House)
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 4)
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 5)
    - New Hampshire Avenue, NW (Near Dupont Circle), undated (Item 6)
      People walking along sidewalk
  - Howard University (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 1)
      View of university from across McMillan Reservoir
    - Howard University, undated (Item 2)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 3)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 4)
  - Middle East House – New Hampshire Avenue (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Middle East House – New Hampshire Avenue, undated (Item 1)
      Three men with fishing rods and caught fish
    - Middle East House – New Hampshire Avenue, undated (Item 2)
      People sitting on park benches in Dupont Circle
    - Middle East House – New Hampshire Avenue, undated (Item 3)
    - Middle East House – New Hampshire Avenue, undated (Item 4)
  - R Street Porte Cochere (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - R Street Porte Cochere, undated (Item 1)
      House on R Street?
    - R Street Porte Cochere, undated (Item 2)
    - R Street Porte Cochere, undated (Item 3)
      Porte Cochere on R Street house
    - R Street Porte Cochere, undated (Item 4)
    - R Street Porte Cochere, undated (Item 5)
  - Kennedy Center (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 1)
      People at art show
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 2)
      Ceiling/chandeliers at the Kennedy Center
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 3)
      John Kennedy bust at Kennedy Center
    - Kennedy Center, undated (Item 4)
      People in the lobby of the Kennedy Center near bust
  - US Capitol (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 1)
      "Bowl and Board" sign
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 2)
      Statue of Kosciuszko?
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 3)
      Columns with wheat tops in US Capitol
    - US Capitol, undated (Item 4)
  - US Supreme Court (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 1)
      Figure of Justice, west entrance
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 2)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 3)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 4)
  - Howard University (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 1)
      Oliver Otis Howard House
    - Howard University, undated (Item 2)
    - Howard University, undated (Item 3)
      Oliver Otis Howard House and School of Social Work
    - Howard University, undated (Item 4)
  - Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets, undated (Item 1)
      Kids playing in park near Asbury statue
    - Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets, undated (Item 2)
    - Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets, undated (Item 3)
    - Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets, undated (Item 4)
  - Fountain in courtyard (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Fountain in courtyard, undated (Item 1)
      Fountain in courtyard
    - Fountain through iron gate, undated (Item 2)
      Fountain through iron gate
    - Fountain through open iron gate, undated (Item 3)
      Fountain through open iron gate
  - Sheridan Circle (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 1)
      Statue of General Philip Sheridan
    - Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 2)
    - Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 3)
      Dupont Circle fountain
    - Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 4)
    - Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 5)
  - Cedar Hill (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Cedar Hill, undated (Item 1)
      Home of Frederick Douglass
    - Cedar Hill, undated (Item 2)
    - Cedar Hill, undated (Item 3)
  - Albert Gallatin Statue (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Albert Gallatin Statue, undated (Item 1)
      Statue of Gallatin north entrance Treasury building through construction barrier
    - Albert Gallatin Statue, undated (Item 2)
    - Albert Gallatin Statue, undated (Item 3)
      Columns of US Treasury building
  - Parks (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Parks, undated (Item 1)
      Bishop Francis Asbury Statue – 16th and Harvard Streets
    - Parks, undated (Item 2)
      People sitting on park bench (16th and Columbia Road)
    - Parks, undated (Item 3)
      People playing chess on park bench in Dupont Circle
  - Fort Stevens (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Fort Stevens, undated (Item 1)
      Cannon and boy at Fort Stevens
    - Fort Stevens, undated (Item 2)
    - Fort Stevens, undated (Item 3)
      Cannons at Fort Stevens
  - Meridian Hill Park (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 1)
      Joan of Arc Statue
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 2)
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 3)
  - Meridian Hill Park (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 1)
      View of Fountain – from lower level
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 2)
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 3)
      Detail of cupid figure – part of fountain
    - Meridian Hill Park, undated (Item 4)
  - Pakistan Embassy (Various Views) (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Pakistan Embassy (Various Views), undated (Item 1)
      2313 Massachusetts Avenue
    - Pakistan Embassy (Various Views), undated (Item 2)
    - Pakistan Embassy (Various Views), undated (Item 3)
    - Pakistan Embassy (Various Views), undated (Item 4)
  - General Philip Sheridan Statue – Sheridan Circle (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - General Philip Sheridan Statue – Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 1)
      Sheridan Statue
    - General Philip Sheridan Statue – Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 2)
    - General Philip Sheridan Statue – Sheridan Circle, undated (Item 3)
  - National Portrait Gallery (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - National Portrait Gallery, undated (Item 1)
      Lincoln Gallery
    - National Portrait Gallery, undated (Item 2)
    - National Portrait Gallery, undated (Item 3)
    - National Portrait Gallery, undated (Item 4)
    - National Portrait Gallery, undated (Item 5)
  - Jefferson Memorial (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Jefferson Memorial, undated (Item 1)
      Boy looking up at statue
    - Jefferson Memorial, undated (Item 2)
      Man walking by statue
    - Jefferson Memorial, undated (Item 3)
      Statue
  - Ledroit Park (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 1)
      House on T Street
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 2)
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 3)
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 4)
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 5)
    - Ledroit Park, undated (Item 6)
  - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue, undated (Item 1)
      Close view of the statue
    - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue, undated (Item 2)
    - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue, undated (Item 3)
    - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue, undated (Item 4)
    - Edward Hopkins Gallaudet Statue, undated (Item 5)
  - Adams Memorial (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Adams Memorial, undated (Item 1)
      "Grief" statue – Rock Creek Cemetery
    - Adams Memorial, undated (Item 2)
    - Adams Memorial, undated (Item 3)
  - US Marine Corps Barracks (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - US Marine Corps Barracks, undated (Item 1)
      Parade Ground
    - US Marine Corps Barracks, undated (Item 2)
    - US Marine Corps Barracks, undated (Item 3)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Plate in store window
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Phone booths
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
      Buildings on H Street, NW
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
      Buddha statue in store window
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Display in Chinatown
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Swords in dojo
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
      Karate lesson
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
      Statues in store window
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Jade Palace Restaurant
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Items in store window
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Chinatown Tropicals store
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
      China Inn
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Chinese Community Church
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
      Webster School
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
      Calvary Baptist Church
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      Ho Yung Chop Suey
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Chinatown Market
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
      Chinese-American Legion
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
      Chinese banners
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
      Store window
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      On Leong Chinese Merchants Association
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Chinese Imports store
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 5)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 6)
  - Chinatown (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 1)
      People in an office
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 2)
      Man sitting at a desk
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 3)
    - Chinatown, undated (Item 4)
  - Reflecting Pool (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Reflecting Pool, undated (Item 1)
      People ice skating – Washington Monument in background
    - Reflecting Pool, undated (Item 2)
      People ice skating – Lincoln Memorial in background
    - Reflecting Pool, undated (Item 3)
    - Reflecting Pool, undated (Item 4)
  - C and O Canal (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - C and O Canal, undated (Item 1)
      Paddle boat on Tidal Basin
    - C and O Canal, undated (Item 2)
      People sitting on folding chairs on National Mall
    - C and O Canal, undated (Item 3)
      Barge on C and O Canal – Georgetown
    - C and O Canal, undated (Item 4)
  - Grant Memorial (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Grant Memorial, undated (Item 1)
      Cavalry group on memorial
    - Grant Memorial, undated (Item 2)
    - Grant Memorial, undated (Item 3)
    - Grant Memorial, undated (Item 4)
  - The Summer House (Olmsted Grotto) (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - The Summer House (Olmsted Grotto), undated (Item 1)
      Capitol Summer House
    - The Summer House (Olmsted Grotto), undated (Item 2)
    - The Summer House (Olmsted Grotto), undated (Item 3)
    - The Summer House (Olmsted Grotto), undated (Item 4)
      Steps and iron railing (location unknown)
  - US Supreme Court (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - US Supreme Court, undated (Item 1)